23,976
Sub 2 Smi : oLdBoY
서기 2029년, LA
1997년 8월 29일 지구의 30억
인구는 종말을 맞이했다
3 billion human lives
ended on August 29th, 1997.
The survivors of the nuclear fire
called the war Judgment Day.
이 핵전쟁에서 살아남은 자들은
이 날을 '심판의 날' 이라고 했고
그때부터 인간은 기계들과
They lived only
to face a new nightmare,
또 다른 전쟁을 시작했다
the war against the machines.
이 기계들을 조종하는 스카이넷은
The computer which
controlled the machines, Skynet,
sent two terminators
back through time.
지금까지 미래에서 현재로
두 터미네이터를 보냈는데
그들의 임무는 반란군 지도자인
내 아들 존 코너를
Their mission: to destroy the leader
of the human resistance:
제거하는 것이었다
John Connor. My son.
첫 번째 터미네이터는
존이 태어나기 전에
The first terminator was programmed
to strike at me
1984년에
in the year 1984.
before John was born.
날 죽이려고 왔지만
It failed.
실패했고
두 번째 터미네이터는
아직 어린 존을
The second was set to strike
at John himself,
죽이기 위해서 왔다
when he was still a child.
첫 번째처럼 반란군 쪽도
존을 보호하기 위해
As before, the Resistance
was able to send a lone warrior.
수호자를 보냈는데
A protector for John.
문제는 어느 쪽이 먼저
존에게 오느냐 였다
It was just a question of which one
of them would reach him first.
주연/ 아놀드 슈워제네거
터미네이터 2
(심판의 날)
린다 해밀턴
로버트 패트릭
조이 모턴
에드워드 펄롱
각본/ 제임스 카메론
월리엄 위셔
감독/ 제임스 카메론
사이즈 맞음
I need your clothes, your boots,
and your motorcycle.
당신 옷과 신발, 오토바이를
좀 빌릴까?
그럼 공손하게 부탁해야지
You forgot to say 'please'.
어떻게 좀 해줘
칼 좀 빼 줘! 칼!
가져가
Take it.
멋대로 가져갈 순 없지
You can't leave and take
the man's wheels, son.
쏘기 전에 어서 내려
Now get off before I put you down.
더 이상 다가오지 마
That's it, goddammit!
순찰차 31번 데이비드다
Art 31 David show me code 6
산타 페 60번가 다리 점검 중
전기 누전으로 보이는 문제발생!
at the 6th street bridge in Santa F?
on an electrical disturbance.
알았습니다, 31번 데이비드
10-4. 31 David.
존 코너
10살 남자, 백인
법적 보호인 : 토드와 자넬
주소 : 19828, 알몬드 가
John! Get in there
and clean up that pigsty of yours.
존, 올라가서 네 방 좀
청소하지 그러니
네 양부모는 정말 못 말리겠다
Your foster-parents
are kinda dicks, huh?
저 애한텐 정말 질렸어요
I swear I've had it
with that goddamn kid.
- 이젠 말대꾸도 안 하잖아요
- 비켜 봐
Won't even answer me anymore.
- Honey. move!
당신이 날 좀 도와줘요
Would you get off your butt
and help me?
- 토드!
- 왜 그래?
Todd.
- What?
제 방 청소를 한 달째
안 하고 있다고요
He hasn't cleaned that room of his
in a month.
알았어, 비상사태군
내가 알아서 처리할게
Oh, it's an emergency.
Hang on, I'll get right on it.
- 어서 타!
- 존!
John! Come on get your ass inside,
do what your mother tells you!
엄마 말대로 네 방은
네가 좀 치우렴
엄만 무슨 엄마예요
She's not my mother. Todd !
페스카데로 정신병원
This next patient is interesting.
Been following the case for years.
다음 환자는 참 흥미로워요
제가 몇 년간 연구를 했는데
올해 29살 된 여성으로
29-year-old female...
...diagnosed as acute
schizo-affective disorder.
심각한 정신분열증 환자인데
그 대표적 증상으로는
절망감과 분노, 폭력
Depression, anxiety, violent
acting-out, delusions of persecution.
피해 망상적 환상이 있죠
특히 환상부분이 아주 독특해요
The delusional architecture
is fairly unique.
그녀 말로는 인간을 닮은
터미네이터라는 기계가
She believes in a machine
called a "terminator",
자신을 죽이기 위해서
미래에서 왔다고
which looks human of course, was
sent back through time to kill her.
- 믿고 있어요
- 독창적이네요
이 환자는 아들의 아버지도
That's original!
And also that the father of her child
was a soldier.
자신을 보호하기 위해
sent back to protect her.
- No.
미래에서 온 전사래요
He was from the future too.
The year 2029,
내 기억이 맞다면 그 미래가
아마 2029년일 거요
if I remember correctly.
다 왔군요
Here we are.
잘 있었소, 사라?
Morning, Sarah.
안녕하세요, 실버맨 박사님!
무릎은 어떠세요?
Good morning, Dr. Silberman.
How's the knee?
괜찮소
Fine, Sarah.
일 주일 전에 만년필로
내 무릎을 찔렀죠
She stabbed me in the kneecap
with my pen a few weeks ago.
또 탈출을 할 모양이지?
Repeated escape attempts.
이제 갑시다
Let's move on, shall we?
또 규칙을 어기고
난리를 피우면 안 돼요
I don't like to see the patients
disrupting their rooms.
- 진정제를 한 대 놓고 살피게
- 제가 직접 하겠습니다
See that she takes her Thorazine.
- I'll take care of it.
약 먹을 시간이야
Time to take you meds, Connor.
당신이나 먹어!
You take it.
자, 얌전히 굴어
You gotta be good.
You're up for review this afternoon.
오늘 오후에
재조사가 있을 거야
안 먹어
말썽 일으키고 싶지 않아
I'm not taking it.
I don't want any trouble.
- Ain't no trouble...
말썽은 무슨...
붙잡아!
Yeah, zap her.
마지막이야!
Last call, sugar.
잘 자라구
Sweet dreams.
Are you the legal guardian
of John Connor?
존 코너의 보호자 되십니까?
네, 그렇습니다
무슨 일이라도 저질렀나요?
That's right.
What's he done now?
Could I speak with him, please?
- 존과 얘기 좀 하고 싶은데요
- 지금 여기 있지도 않아요
Could if he was here.
아침 일찍 오토바이를 타고
나갔거든요
He took off on his bike.
So he could be anywhere.
존의 사진 있습니까?
Do you have a photo of John?
Yeah, sure, hold on.
네, 잠깐만요
You gonna tell me
what this is about?
이번엔 무슨 일이죠?
I just need to ask him
a few questions.
몇 가지 물어볼 게 있어서요
잘 생겼군요
사진을 제가 가져가도 될까요?
He's a good looking boy.
Mind if I keep this picture?
- No, go on.
그러세요! 아침에도 어떤
남자가 그 애를 찾았어요
There was a guy here
looking for him too.
오토바이를 탄 덩치 큰 남자였죠
Big guy on a bike. Has that
got something to do with this?
그자와 관련된 일인가보죠?
아닙니다, 걱정할 것 없습니다
No. I wouldn't worry about him.
협조해줘서 감사합니다
Thanks for your cooperation.
훔친 카드를 넣어주세요
Please insert your stolen card now!
PIN number...
암호가...
Hurry up,
this is taking too long!
서둘러!
시간이 너무 걸리잖아
제발 좀 맞아라
Go baby, go baby...
Alright! PIN number...
됐어!
- 암호는 9003
- 어디서 그런 걸 배웠니?
Who did you learn this from?
- My mom.
진짜 엄마한테
My real mom, I mean.
얼마를 꺼낼까... 300불!
Withdraw 300 bucks.
Come on, baby, come on...
나와라, 나와라!
- 그렇지!
- 와, 해냈구나!
It worked !
좋았어
돈 벌기 너무 쉬운데!
Easy money! Come on!
누워서 떡 먹기야!
Yeah!
- Piece of cake!
- 네 엄마니?
- 응
That her?
Yes.
정말 미인이시다
So she's pretty cool, huh?
- No, she's a complete psycho.
아니, 정말 싸이코지
That's why she's up at Pescadero,
the mental institute.
증상이 심해
정신병원에 계셔
컴퓨터 공장을 폭파시키려다
총상을 입고 체포됐지
Tried to blow up
the computer factory,
but got shot and arrested.
- Oh shit.
저런!
She's a total loser.
인생의 실패자야
Come on,
let's go spend some money!
돈이나 쓰러 가자
사라...
Sarah.
사라, 어서 깨요!
Sarah, wake up.
카일!
Kyle?
You're dead.
당신은 죽었잖아요!
우리 아들은 어딨소?
Where's our son, Sarah?
그들이 데려가 버렸어요
They took him away from me.
- 놈들이 존을 노리고 있어
- 알아요
He's the target now.
- I know!
He's alone.
You have to protect him.
그 아이는 당신이 지켜줘야만 해
I know.
알고 있어요
You tell me how I am supposed
to do that.
어떻게 해야 할지 말해줘요
He doesn't even
believe me anymore.
그 아인 나를 안 믿어요
- 내가 졌어요
- 당신은 강해, 사라
I've lost him.
You're strong, Sarah.
당신이 생각하는 것보다
훨씬 더 강해
Stronger than you ever thought.
- No.
On your feet, soldier!
기운 차려!
사랑해, 사라
I love you. I always will.
영원히...
I need you.
- I'll always be with you.
당신이 필요해요
난 늘 당신과 함께요
그 메시지 기억하지?
Remember the message?
미래는 정해진 게 아니다
"The future is not set.
운명이란 없으며
우리가 만들어 갈 뿐이다
There is no fate
but what we make for ourselves."
가지 말아요
Stay with me.
There's not much time left
in the world, Sarah.
시간이 얼마 안 남았소, 사라
카일, 가지 말아요!
Kyle, don't go!
카일!
Kyle!
거대한 섬광 같은 것이
It's like a giant strobe light,
burning right to my eyes.
바로 눈앞에서 타올랐어요
아직도 생생해요
Somehow I can still see.
오, 하느님!
Look,
꿈은 매일 똑같아요
we know the dream's the same
every night, why do we have to...
- 왜 매일 이런...
- 계속하십시오
Please continue.
애들은 다 타버린 종이 같았죠
The children look like burnt paper.
시커멓게 말이죠
black.
꼼짝도 안 했어요
not moving.
그리고 핵풍이 밀어닥쳤어요
Then the blast wave hits them...
그리고는 애들을 날려버렸어요
...and they fly apart like leaves.
꿈이오
종말에 대한 그런 꿈은
Dreams about the end of the world
are very common, Sarah.
흔히 있는 현상이죠
이건 꿈이 아니고
진짜 현실이에요
It's not a dream, you moron.
It's real.
- 그 날은 분명 온다고요
- 진짜처럼 느껴질 뿐이오
I know the date it happens!
- I'm sure it feels real to you.
1997년 8월 29일
On August 29th, 1997 it's going to
feel pretty fucking real to you too!
그 참사는 당신도
예외일 수는 없어요
Anybody not wearing
two million sunblock
지구의 모든 인류가
그 날이 되면 죽게 된다고
is gonna have
a real bad day, get it?
알아들어요?
맙소사, 당신은 안전하게
살 것 같아?
God, you think
you're safe and alive.
다 죽는 거야
모두 죽는다고!
You're already dead. Everybody.
him, you, you're dead already!
여기 있는 모두와
병원까지 끝장이야
This place,
everything you see, is gone.
You're the one living
in a fucking dream, Silberman!
미친 건 바로 당신이야!
난 이미 알고 있어!
Because I know it happens.
분명 그 날이 온다구!
It happens!
전 많이 좋아졌어요
I feel much better now.
상당히...
Clearer.
그래요, 당신 태도가 최근
Yes. Your attitude has been
much improved lately.
많이 좋아진 건 사실이오
목표를 가졌거든요
It has helped to have a goal,
앞날에 대한 희망이죠
something to look forward to.
그게 뭐지?
And what is that?
그러니까 박사님이...
You said that if I showed
improvement after six months,
6개월 전에, 제 병이 호전되면
다른 보호소로 옮기고
you would transfer me
to the minimum security wing
사람도 만날 수 있다고 했어요
and I could have visitors.
지금 6개월이 지났어요
Well, it's been six months.
그리고...
I was looking forward
to seeing my son.
전 사랑하는 아들이
보고 싶어요
알겠소
I see.
당신이 말하던
그 터미네이터 얘긴데
Let's go back
to what you were saying
about those terminator machines.
Now you think they don't exist?
이젠 존재하진 않나요?
그런 건 없어요
They don't exist.
I know that now.
이제야 알겠어요
But you've told me
on many occasions
당신이 그들 중의 하나를
폭파한 얘기를 여러 번
about how you crushed one
in a hydraulic press.
내게 들려줬는데
정말 그랬다면 흔적이라도
남아 있어야죠
If I had, there would have been
some evidence.
아무것도 못 찾았다면서요
They would've found
something at the factory.
그렇군요
I see.
이젠 회사가 그 일을 숨긴다고
생각진 않아요?
So you don't believe anymore
that the company covered it up?
아뇨, 뭐 하러 그러겠어요?
No, why would they?
좋아, 다른 위치에서 해보죠
Let's try a new position.
Right, there.
The neuronal sensors are correct,
because it works.
The neurons are all centered.
Maybe the inhibitors failed.
다이슨 씨?
Mr. Dyson?
The materials team...
설비 팀이...
- 다이슨 씨!
- 네
오늘 설비 팀이 오후에
다른 실험을 한답니다
...is running another series
this afternoon, and you have to...
그래서 그게 필요하대요
You have to sign it out.
- 가져오실 거죠?
- 그렇게 하죠
Come on. I'll get it.
다이슨 씨, 전 여기 온 지 얼마
안 됐지만 궁금한 게 많아요
I know I haven't been here that long,
but I was wondering if you know...
뭘 말인가?
Know what?
그걸 어디서 구했어요?
Well if you know,
where it came from.
나도 똑같은 질문을
그들에게 했더니
I asked the same question once.
Know what they told me?
묻지도 말라고 하더군
"Don't ask."
- 안녕하세요?
- 잘 있었나?
Hello, Mr. Dyson. - How's it going?
- Okay.
네, 열쇠 넣었죠?
셋에 돌리세요!
Insert key.
Left and three, two, one, turn.
2, 1, 돌려!
- 가족들은 잘 있죠?
- 물론이지
How are wife and kids?
- Great, thanks.
어떻게 생각하시죠?
So what do you think, Doctor?
제가 좀 나아졌죠
I've shown improvement.
haven't l?
글쎄, 사라
문제가 좀 있는 것 같군
Well, Sarah, here's the problem:
당신이 똑똑한 건 알아
I know how smart you are.
당신은 내가 듣고 싶은
말만 했어
You're just telling me
what I want to hear.
당신이 오늘 한 말
다 진심이 아닌 것 같거든
I don't think you believe
what you're telling me.
만약 딴 보호소로 옮기면
또 탈출을 할거잖아
If I put you in minimum security
you'll just try to escape again.
아들을 보게 해주세요
You have to let me see my son.
Please.
부탁해요
그 앤 위험에 처해 있어요
제가 있어야 돼요
He's in great danger.
He's naked without me.
전화 한 통만이라도...
If I could just make a phone call.
- I'm afraid not. Not for a while.
미안해, 당분간은 안 돼
딴 방법이 없군
다음 6개월 간도 정상적으로
I don't see any choice but to
recommend to the review board
견딜 수 있는지 지켜봐야겠소
that you stay here
for another six months.
이 자식, 죽여버리겠어!
You son of a bitch!
나쁜 자식!
소디움 10cc를 주사해
안 돼, 무슨 짓이야? 이거 놔!
You don't know what you're doing!
- Straighten her now!
어서 가져와
무슨 짓을 하는지 아냐구!
You don't know what you're doing!
특별환자답군
Model citizen.
신분 확인됨
방금 여기를 지나갔는데요
You just missed him.
He left fifteen minutes ago.
- 갤러리아에 간다고 그랬어요
- 맞아
I think he said he was going to
the Galleria. - Yeah.
갤러리아?
The Galleria?
동전 바꿔올게, 금방 올게
I'll get some quarters.
I'll be back, alright?
- 오, 안 돼!
- 존 코너를 아니?
Girls, do you know John Connor?
- No.
이 애를 아니?
You know this guy?
몰라요
No, I don't know him.
- 존
- 조금만 기다려
John.
- Not now.
이봐, 경찰이 널 찾고 있어
There's this cop scoping for you.
check it out.
- 저기 있어요!
- 갈라지자!
Split, man, just go.
- Yeah.
- 어서 도망쳐!
- 그래!
아까 찾으시던 그 애...
I think I saw the kid
you're looking for.
꼬마야! 여긴 들어오면 안 돼
You're not supposed to be here!
엎드려
Get down!
괜찮으세요?
괜찮아요?
제발!
Come on!
젠장!
Goddamn!
됐어요, 좀 멈춰요
오토바이 세워요
Okay, time out. Stop the bike!
시합 끝났으니
좀 멈춰보라고요!
Come on, stop the bike.
일을 어렵게 하지 말자고요
Don't take this the wrong way.
you're a terminator, right?
- 당신은 터미네이터죠?
- 그래
Yes. Cyberdyne Systems, Model 101 .
사이버다인 모델 101이다
맙소사!
Holy shit! You're really real!
진짜군요
그러니까...
당신 내부는 기계 맞죠?
You're like a machine underneath.
but sort of alive outside?
하지만 겉은 살아있죠?
난 인공지능 로봇이지만
I'm a cybernetic organism.
겉은 생체 세포로 덮여 있다
Living tissue
over a metal endoskeleton.
이럴 수가...
This is intense.
정신 좀 차리자
Get a grip, John.
날 죽이러 온 게
You're not here to kill me.
I figured that out for myself.
아니란 걸 알겠어요
그럼 이유가 뭐죠?
So what's the deal?
내 임무는 널 보호하는 거다
My mission is to protect you.
그래요? 누가 보냈어요?
Yeah? Who sent you?
바로 너!
You did.
35년 후의 네가
자신을 지키기 위해
35 years from now
you reprogrammed me
미래에서 날 보낸 것이다
to be your protector here.
in this time.
정말 모르겠군요
This is deep.
This other guy.
he's a terminator like you, right?
쫓아오던 자도
당신 같은 터미네이터죠?
나하고는 달라
그는 개량형인 T-1000이야
Not like me. A T-1000.
Advanced prototype.
You mean more advanced
than you are?
당신보다 진보된 기계인가요?
그래, 유동멀티합금이다
Yes. A mimetic polyalloy.
그게 뭐예요?
What does that mean?
액체 금속이지
Liquid metal.
어디로 가죠?
Where are we going?
- We have to get out of the city.
빨리 도시에서 벗어나야 해
여기서는 시끄러워져
And avoid the authorities.
그럼 집에 잠깐 들러요
저도 제 무기가 필요하잖아요
I gotta stop by my house
and pick up some stuff. - Negative.
안 돼! T-1000이 널 잡으러
기다리고 있을 거다
The T-1000 will definitely
try to reacquire you there.
- 확실해요?
- 나라면 그런다
You sure?
- I would.
제겐 양부모가 계세요
Look, Todd and Janelle are dicks
전화나 한 통 해드리구요
but I gotta warn them.
이런, 동전 있어요?
Shit! You got a quarter?
- 여보세요?
- 저예요
Hello?
Janelle? It's me.
- 존!
- 네, 아무 일 없죠?
John?
- Yeah.
- 두분 다 괜찮으세요?
- 물론이지, 별일 없어
Is everything alright?
- Sure.
- 넌 괜찮니?
- 네, 좋아요
Are you alright?
- I'm fine.
존, 늦었다
안 그래도 걱정하고 있었어
John, it's late. I was
beginning to worry about you.
빨리 와서 저녁 같이 먹자, 존
If you hurry, we can have dinner
together. I'm making beef stew.
쇠고기 스튜를 만들었단다
이상한데요
너무 상냥해요
Something's wrong.
She's never this nice.
존, 거기 어디지?
Where are you?
저놈의 개가 왜 저렇게 짖지?
What's the goddamn dog
barking at?
조용히 해, 이 쓸모 없는 것아!
Shut up.
you piece of shit!
개가 짖고 있어요
The dog's barking.
저 미친개를 존에게
치우라고 안 했어?
Tell the kid
to get rid of that mutt.
존, 늦었다
네가 너무 걱정되는구나
Honey, it's late.
벌써 온 걸까요?
Could it already be there?
괜찮니?
Are you okay?
- 전 정말 괜찮아요
- 그래? 정말 괜찮은 거지?
I'm right here. I'm fine.
- Are you sure?
- 개 이름이 뭐지?
- 맥스요
What's the dog's name?
- Max.
울피가 왜 저래요?
Janelle, what's wrong with Wolfy?
짖는 게 여기서도 들려요
괜찮아요?
I can hear him barking.
Is he okay?
울피는 괜찮아
걱정 마라
Wolfy's fine, honey.
어디에 있지?
Where are you?
너희 양부모는 죽었어
Your foster-parents are dead.
잠깐, 잠깐만요
I need a minute here.
그가 손만 대면 무슨 형태로도
다 복제가 된단 말이죠?
You're telling me that this thing
can imitate anything it touches?
육체적 접촉만 해도 다 가능하다
Anything it samples
by physical contact.
믿을 수 없어요
Can't be real!
담배 갑으로도 변할 수가 있나요?
It could disguise itself
as a pack of cigarettes?
크기가 비슷한 것만 돼
Only objects of equal size.
폭탄으로 변해
날 죽이면 되잖아요
Why not a bomb
or something to get me?
It can't form complex machines.
Guns, explosives have chemicals.
폭탄물이나 화약 같은
복잡한 결합구조는
변형이 불가능하지만
moving parts.
It doesn't work that way.
- 단단한 금속 형태는 가능하지
- 예를 들면요?
But it can form solid metal shapes.
Like what?
- Knives and stabbing weapons.
칼이나 찌르는 흉기들
이것은 1984년 서부지역
하일랜드 경찰서에서
These were taken
by a video surveillance camera
비디오 감시 카메라로 찍은 거요
at the West Highland police station
in 1984.
그날 밤,
그는 경찰 17명을 죽였소
He killed 17 police officers
that night.
모두 가족이 있었지
Men with families.
애들까지
Children.
이건 오늘 쇼핑몰에서 찍힌 거요
These were taken
at a mall in Reseda. Today.
바로 오늘
코너 부인, 당신은 분명
이 자를 알고 있어요
Ms Connor, we know
you know who this guy is.
난 지금 당신 아들의 실종과
Look, I just sat here
and told you your son is missing,
양부모의 살해 얘기를 하고 있소
that the foster-parents
have been murdered.
이 자와 관련이 있단 말이오
We know this guy's involved.
무슨 말이든 해봐요
걱정도 안 돼요?
Doesn't that mean anything to you?
Don't you care?
시간 낭비군
We're wasting our time.
가지
Let's go.
미안합니다
Sorry, guys. She's just grown
more and more disconnected
시간이 흐를수록 점점
현실과 동떨어져 가고 있어요
from reality as time goes on.
도움이 못 돼서 죄송하군요
I'm afraid she can't help us now.
기억을 찾으면 연락 드리죠
If she clears at all and can give us
anything, I'll call you. - Sure.
좋습니다
더글라스, 방으로 데려가게
Douglas, take her
back to her room, please. - Yes, sir.
네
자, 우리도 올라갈까요?
Come on, let's go.
엄마와 난...
대부분 니콰라과 같은
남미에서 지냈어요
We spent a lot of time
in Nicaragua and places like that.
엄마는 퇴역 공수부대원과 함께
For a while she was
with this crazy ex-Green Beret guy.
총을 밀수했죠
running guns.
다른 사람도 많았어요
Then there were some other guys.
거기서 엄마는 여러 가지를 배워
She'd shack up with anybody
she could learn from.
절 최고의 군사 지휘관으로
만들려고 가르치셨죠
so she could teach me
how to be this great military leader.
엄만 그 때 잘못 되신 거예요
Then she gets busted and it's like:
다들 엄마가 정신병자인 걸
몰랐냐고 묻더군요
"Sorry kid, your mom's a psycho.
Didn't you know?"
엄마가 해준 모든 게
엉터리라고 생각하면서
Everything I've been brought up
to believe is all bullshit.
전 엄마를 증오했어요
I hated her for that.
그런데 엄마 말씀이 사실이었군요
But everything she said was true.
엄마는 알았지만...
She knew.
아무도 안 믿었죠
And nobody believed her.
저까지도요
Not even me.
엄마를 거기서 탈출시켜야 돼요
We gotta get her out of there.
- Negative.
안 돼, T-1000은
상당한 지능을 갖고 있다
The T-1000's highest
probability for success will be
우리가 찾아갈 걸 알고
사라를 복제해놓고 기다릴 거다
to copy her and wait
for you to make contact.
그럼 엄마는 어떡해요?
Great, What happens to her?
대개 복제된 대상은 제거되지
The subject being copied
is terminated.
이런, 진작 말 했어야죠
빨리 가요!
Why didn't you tell me?
We gotta go now!
Negative.
It's not a priority.
안 돼
그건 최선의 행동이 아냐
젠장, 나한테는 최선이에요
Fuck you.
she's a priority to me!
제기랄, 왜 이래요?
도와줘요
Goddammit!
What's your problem?
Help!
- This does not help our mission!
이런 행동은 도움이 안 돼
도와줘요
이 정신병자를 데려가요
Help me! Get this psycho off of me.
이자가 나를 해치려 해요
도와줘요
이 손, 놔!
Let me go!
이게 무슨 짓이에요?
Why did you do that?
네가 명령했잖아
Because you told me to.
그래요?
What?
내 명령대로 한다구요?
You have to do what I say?
임무수칙 중 하나다
One of my mission parameters.
증명해봐요
한 발로 서봐요
Prove it.
Stand on one foot.
좋아!
정말 터미네이터로군요
Cool! My own terminator.
괜찮니?
You okay, kid?
꺼져, 이 멍청아
Take a hike, bozo.
야, 그냥 가자
Let's get out of here.
- What?
손 좀 봐줄까, 이 꼬맹아?
Fuck you, Iittle dipshit.
꼬맹이?
Dipshit?
발 내려요
Put your leg down.
- 나보고 방금 꼬맹이라고 했냐?
- 이런 놈을 도우러 왔다니...
Did you call moi a dipshit?
Just trying to help this punk.
이 녀석 혼 좀 내줘
Grab this guy.
내려 줘! 내려 줘!
누구보고 꼬맹이래?
Now who's the dipshit.
you jock douchebag?
이 푸대자루 같은 놈아
안 돼요!
총 내려놔요, 빨리요!
Put the gun down! Now!
- 어서 꺼져!
- 야, 빨리 도망가자
Get out of here!
Come on, let's split!
사람을 죽일 뻔했잖아요
You were gonna kill that guy!
당연하지
난 터미네이터니까
Of course. I'm a terminator.
이봐요, 내 말 잘 들어요
Listen to me carefully, okay?
이젠 터미네이터가 아녜요
알겠어요?
You're not
a terminator anymore. Alright?
알았냐구요!
You got that?
사람을 죽이면 안 돼요!
You just can't go round
killing people! - Why?
왜?
- 글쎄, 안 된다면 안 돼요!
- 왜?
What do you mean "why"?
'Cause you can't!
Why?
- Because you just can't, okay?
여하튼 그건 안 돼요
그냥 날 믿어요
Trust me on this.
전 엄마를 구하러 갈 거예요
Look, I'm gonna go get my mom.
이건 명령이에요, 도와줘요
And I order you to help me.
사라 코너 있소?
You have a Sarah Connor here?
- You're running kind of late.
늦게 오셨군요
다들 온 지 1시간도 넘었는데
They've been in there for an hour.
Hold on a second, I'll buzz you in.
잠깐만 기다리세요
알려드릴게요
오, 동료들이 나오는군요
Oh, here come your friends now.
- 커피 한 잔 갖다 줄까?
- 괜찮아요
Hey Gwen, you want some coffee?
- No, thanks.
- 맥주는 없나요?
- 그거 좋지
How about a beer?
- Yeah, right.
- 풀 하우스잖아
- 잘 됐군요
I got a Full House.
- That's good.
오늘 운이 좋군
Must be my lucky day.
24호실 환자한테 그 주사를 놔
Yeah, I think you're right
about number 24.
250mg 투약해
Increase the medication
to 250 milligrams.
- 한꺼번에요?
- 응
Same time?
- Yeah.
당신!
내 팔을 부러뜨렸어
You broke my arm !
네 몸에 있는 215개의 뼈 중
There's 215 bones
in the human body. That's one.
고작 한 개가 부러진 거야
Now don't move!
뭐 하는 거야?
What are you gonna do?
왜 멈추라는 거지?
Why do we stop now?
사람을 죽이지 않겠다고
약속해요
You gotta promise
you're not gonna kill anyone, right?
- 알았다
- 맹세하죠?
Right.
- Swear.
뭐라고?
What?
손을 들고 죽이지 않겠다고
맹세해요
Just put up your hand and say
"I swear I won't kill anyone."
난 사람을 절대 죽이지
않겠다고 맹세한다
I swear I will not kill anyone.
- Alright, let's go.
그럼 이제 가요
방문 시간은
10시에서 4시까지예요
Visiting hours is 10 to 4.
Monday through Friday.
주말은 빼고
무슨 짓이에요?
What are you doing?
이 나쁜 놈!
날 쏘다니...
You son of a bitch! You shot me!
이런 미친 놈!
그만... 그만해! 살려줘
죽이진 않았어
He'll live.
이런, 맙소사
Son of a bitch!
모두 진정하고 침착해
Let's all try to remain calm.
- Open it or he'll be dead!
빨리 열어
박사가 죽는 꼴을 보고 싶나?
그렇게는 안 돼
박사님을 놔 줘
There's no way, Connor. Let him go.
- 문 열라니까
- 그렇게는 못 해
Open the door!
- It ain't gonna happen.
진정해, 사라
Take it easy, Sarah.
당신은 절대 살인은 못 해
내가 장담하지
It won't work, Sarah.
You're no killer.
You're already dead, Silberman.
당신 모두는 이미 죽은 목숨이야
난 알아
Everybody here dies.
So don't fuck with me!
허튼 수작 하지 마
문 열어!
Open the door.
비켜!
Back off!
Get back or I'll pump him
full of this shit. I swear!
물러서지 않으면 끝장이다
농담 아냐
움직이지 마
Don't move!
막대기를 내려 놔!
Drop the shit!
내려 놔!
Do it! Do it!
사무실 안으로 들어가
Get in the office!
바닥에 엎드려
그리고 당신!
On the floor! Face down! Not you!
당신은 문 열어
Open the door!
엎드려!
On the floor! Hold it open!
Face the wall!
벽을 향해서 엎드려
빨리 잡아, 빨리!
Get her!
문을 열어! 잠겼어!
어서 빨리 열어!
Come on, open it!
Come on!
- 열쇠가 부러졌어
- 문 열어!
She just broke it off.
- Open it.
놓치면 안 돼, 빨리!
어서 가!
Let's go around, come on!
Move it!
No!
엄마, 기다려요!
Mom! Wait!
이리 와!
No!
- 도와줘요
- 여기서 기다려
Help her.
- Wait here.
- 서둘러!
- 우릴 죽일 거야
He'll kill us all!
꽉 잡아!
우리 모두 죽일 거야
He'll kill us all!
엄마, 괜찮아요? 엄마!
Mom, are you okay?
살고 싶으면 따라 오시오
Come with me.
if you want to live.
괜찮아요, 엄마!
우릴 도우러 왔어요
It's okay, Mom.
He's here to help.
어서 가
Go!
도대체 무슨 일이야?
무슨 일이냐구?
What the fuck is going on?
엎드려
Get down!
차에서 내려!
Out of the car!
당장!
Right now!
가요
총알이 없어
I'm out.
- 빨리!
- 여기요!
Come on!
- Here.
장전해
Reload !
마지막이에요
Next one.
꽉 잡아!
Hang on!
됐어요
Ready!
운전하시오
Here, drive!
안 따라와요
아무도 없어요
There's nobody behind us.
- 너, 괜찮니?
- 네
Are you alright?
- Yeah.
다 제대로 보이나요?
Can you even see anything?
아주 잘 보인다
I see everything.
잘 됐네요!
Cool.
이리 와라
Come here.
전 괜찮다니까요
I said I was okay.
존, 병원에 온 건
어리석은 짓이었어
John, it was stupid of you
to go there.
더 현명하게 생각해라
You have to
be smarter than that.
죽을 뻔했잖아
You almost got yourself killed.
What were you thinking?
대체 무슨 생각을 했니?
나를 위해서라면 그런
위험한 짓은 하지 말거라
You cannot risk yourself,
even for me, do you understand?
알아듣겠니?
넌 아주 중요한 인물이야
You're too important!
알았어?
You understand?
하지만...
전 엄마를 구해야 했어요
죄송해요
I had to get you
out of that place. I'm sorry.
네 도움은 필요 없다
나 스스로 지킬 수 있으니까
I didn't need your help.
I can take care of myself.
눈에서 왜 물이 나오지?
What's wrong with your eyes?
아니에요
Nothing.
당신은 어떻게 된 거죠?
So what's your story?
괜찮소?
You okay?
- Fine.
괜찮아요
이거 멋진 오토바이군
Say, that's a nice bike.
이봐요, 조심하라구요
Hey, watch it, lug nuts.
정말, 할 줄 아는 거예요?
Listen,
you know what you are doing?
해부학 지식은 갖고 있다
I have detailed files
on human anatomy.
- I bet.
하긴...
효율적인 제거자가 돼야 하니까
Makes you a more efficient killer,
right? - Correct.
맞아요
총에 맞아도 안 아파요?
Does it hurt when you get shot?
부상은 느낄 수 있지
그걸 고통이라고 하더군
I sense injuries. The data
could be called pain.
존, 불 좀 비춰라
John, help me with the light.
- 이러면 나아질까요?
- 그럼요
Will these heal up?
- Yes.
좋아요, 이 정도는 돼야
우리에게도 쓸모가 있죠
Good. If you can't pass for human,
you're not much good to us.
당신은 얼마나 오랫동안
살 수 있죠?
How long do you live,
I mean "last", whatever?
저장된 파워 기능으로
120년은 버틸 수 있다
120 years with
my existing power cell.
프로그램 되지 않은 것도
알 수 있나요?
Can you learn stuff you
haven't been programmed with?
그러니까...
So you can be...
you know, more human?
좀 더 인간처럼...
되기 위해서 말이에요
Not such a dork all the time?
내 중앙기억장치는
습득방식 컴퓨터로서
My CPU is a neural-net processor.
a learning computer,
접촉이 많을수록 많이 배운다
that Skynet presets to READ
only when we are sent out alone.
생각 많이 하는 거 싫죠?
Doesn't want you
to do too much thinking.
싫어요
No.
다시 설정할 수 있어요?
Can we reset the switch?
시계 반대방향으로
잠금 장치를 돌려요!
Rotate the two locking cylinders
counterclockwise.
어서요!
Do it.
이젠 포트 뚜껑을 열어요
Now open the port cover.
봉함장치를 당겨요
Pull to break the seal.
잘했어요, 다음엔
충격완화 장치를 없애고
Good, now remove
the shock damping assembly.
이제 중앙처리장치에 접근해요
You can now access the CPU.
- 찾았어요?
- 네
Do you see it?
- Yes.
아래 탭을 이용해
중앙처리장치를 꺼내요
Pull the CPU by its base tap.
당겨!
Pull.
핀 스위치 보여요?
Can you see the pin switch?
안 돼요!
No!
- 비켜라, 존
- 죽이지 마요
Out of my way, John!
- Don't kill him!
이건 사람이 아니라
기계일 뿐이야
"It", John, not "him".
기계라고 쳐요!
하지만 우린 이게 필요해요
Okay, "it". But we need "it".
잘 들어라
Listen to me, Listen.
우리는 우리 힘으로 지켜야 해
We're better off on our own.
그는 미래와 전쟁에 관한
He's the only proof of
the future, the war and that.
유일한 증거예요
그럴 지도 모르지
Maybe.
난 저자를 안 믿어
I don't trust it.
내 친구예요, 알아요?
But he's my friend, alright?
이 칩을 없애는 게 뭘 뜻하는지
넌 이해 못해
You don't know what it's like
to kill these things.
상황이 불리해지면 이게
마지막 기회일 수도 있어, 비켜!
If something goes wrong,
this could be our last chance.
엄마 말대로 내가 정말
위대한 리더가 될 거라면
If I'm supposed to
be this military leader,
리더의 생각을 존중하는
법도 연습해 두세요
maybe you start listening
to my ideas once in a while.
엄마조차 무시한다면
'Cause if my own mother won't,
how do you expect anyone else to?
누구한테 그걸 기대하겠어요?
좋아, 네 맘대로 해
Alright, play it your way.
무슨 문제 있었니?
Was there a problem?
아뇨
No problem.
아무 일 없어요
None whatsoever.
아직 많이 배워야겠어요
Are we learning yet?
이봐요, 도시에서 가능한
멀리 도망쳐야 돼요
We have to get as far away
from the city as possible.
남쪽으로 가요
Just head south.
경찰에게 잡히니까
Keep it under 65.
We don't want to be pulled over.
100Km를 유지하도록 해요
- 접수됐소
- 아니, 그게 아녜요
Affirmative.
No, no, no.
사람들이 말하는 걸 잘 들어봐요
You got to listen to
the way people talk.
'접수됐소' 같은
어려운 말 쓰지 말고
You don't say "affirmative"
or some shit like that.
그 땐 '문제없소' 하세요
You say "No problemo".
누가 거드름을 피우면
'그래, 너 잘났다' 하고
If someone comes up to you
with an attitude, you say "Eat me".
상대를 기쁘게 해주려면
' 다음에 또 봐요' 하는 거구요
And if you want to shine them
on, it's "Hasta la vista, baby".
그래, 다음에 또 봐
Hasta la vista, baby.
잘 했어요
Or "Later, dickwad".
또 누군가 열을 받아 화내면
'흥분하지마' 하던가
If someone gets upset
you say "Chill out".
같이 맞장구를 쳐줘요
Or do combinations.
너도 그만 흥분해라
Chill out, dickwad.
좋아요, 잘 했어요
You're getting it.
문제없어
No problemo.
현금 있어?
You got any cash?
- I got a couple of hundred bucks.
200 달러 정도 있어요
절반 줄게요
I'll give you half.
엄마!
Mom!
뭐 좀 먹어라
Get some food.
팍팍하긴...
No sense of humor.
이건 좀 다른 얘긴데
인상 좀 펴고 다녀요
And that's another thing:
Iighten up a bit.
그렇게 폼잡던 시대는 지났어요
This severe routine is getting old.
You're acting like such a geek.
꼭 괴짜처럼 굴고 있잖아요
미소 좀 지어봐요
Smile once in a while.
미소?
Smile?
그래요, 미소요
잘 봐요!
Yeah. You know, smile.
Watch.
안녕하세요? 목이 아주 좋네요
장사는 잘 되세요?
Hi. Nice place you got here.
How's business?
귀찮게 하지 마라
Gimme a break.
하필 잘못 걸렸네요
Okay. Bad example.
저쪽의 남자 보여요?
See that guy over there?
That's a smile.
저런 게 미소예요
좋아요
That's good.
거울 같은 거 보면서
연습 좀 더 해 봐요
You could practice
in front of a mirror or something.
프라이 좀 드릴까요?
Want some of my fries?
도와줄까요?
Do you need any help?
됐어
No.
- 내가 쐈어
- 아니야
Got you!
- No, you didn't!
- You didn't!
우리가 해낼 수 있을까요?
We're not gonna make it, are we?
우리 인간들이요
People, I mean.
인간은 파괴 본능이 있다
It's in your nature
to destroy yourselves.
네, 그래서 걱정돼요
Yeah, Major drag, huh?
자, 그만하고 들어가자
스카이넷은 어떻게 만들어졌고
I need to know
how Skynet gets built.
누가 만들었죠?
Who's responsible?
직접적인 책임은
마일스 베넷 다이슨에게 있어요
The man responsible
is Miles Bennett Dyson.
그가 누구죠?
Who is that?
사이버다인 시스템 회사의
특수 제작부 책임자요
The director of special projects at
Cyberdyne Systems Corporation.
어떻게 그가?
Why him?
그는 몇 달 후, 아주 획기적인
마이크로프로세서를 발명할 거요
In a few months he creates a
revolutionary microprocessor.
계속해요, 그래서?
Go on. Then what?
3년 내에 사이버다인 회사는
세계 최대의 군사용 컴퓨터의
In three years Cyberdyne
will become the largest supplier
공급원이 될 겁니다
of military computer systems.
모든 스텔스 폭격기가 이 컴퓨터의
사용으로 기능이 발전해서
Stealth bombers are upgraded
with Cyberdyne computers.
완전무인 자동생산이 되고
Becoming unmanned,
완벽한 시험 가동에 들어갈 거요
they fly
with a perfect operational record.
스카이넷 연구 기금안이 통과되면서
The Skynet funding bill is passed.
1997년 8월 4일 이후
모든 시스템이 작동됩니다
The system goes on-line
on August 4th, 1997.
국방전략에서 인간의
결정권은 무시되죠
Human decisions are removed
from strategic defense.
스카이넷이 급속도로 발전해
Skynet begins to learn
at a geometric rate.
8월 29일 동부 표준시간
새벽 2시 14분
It becomes self-aware at 2: 14 a.m.
eastern time, August 29.
사람들은 스위치를 끄려고 했소
In a panic,
they try to pull the plug.
- 스카이넷이 대항했겠군요
- 맞아요
Skynet fights back.
미사일을 러시아로 발사시켰죠
Yes. It launches its missiles
against targets in Russia.
왜 러시아죠?
그들에게 두려운 상대였나요?
Why Russia?
They're our friends now.
러시아의 폭격이
미국 내에 있는
Because Skynet knows
that the Russian counterattack
그들의 적들을
위협하리라 믿었었지
will eliminate its enemies here.
- Jesus.
맙소사!
또 다이슨에 대한 건?
How much do you know
about Dyson?
자료는 충분히 갖고 있소
I have detailed files.
모두 알고 싶어요
I want to know everything.
놈의 인상과 주소, 모든 걸요
What he looks like.
Where he lives. Everything.
여보!
Miles!
하루 종일 일할 거야?
You going to work all day?
- I'm sorry, baby.
미안하지만 아주 급한 일이야
This thing
is kicking my ass.
오늘은 일요일이에요
It's Sunday. You promised to take
the kids to Raging Waters today.
아이들 데리고 놀러간다고
약속했잖아
안 돼
I can't. I'm on a roll.
그럴 정신 없어
23,976
여보, 이건 아주 획기적인 거야
This is gonna blow 'em away.
It's a neural-net processor.
- 이건 신경망 칩이야
- 알아요, 말해줬잖아
I know. You told me.
인간처럼 생각하고
배울 수 있지
It thinks and learns like we do.
상온에서도 초전도 기능을
수행할 수 있지
It's superconducting
at room temperature.
다른 컴퓨터는 전자수첩
수준에 불과해
Other computers are just
pocket calculators by comparison.
이게 뭐 그렇게 중요해요?
Why is that so important?
I need to know,
'cause sometimes I feel like
정말 궁금해요
가끔은 내가 미쳐버릴 것 같아
I'm going crazy here.
여보, 거의 다 됐어
Baby, I am this close.
이리 와
Come here.
Imagine a jet airliner
with a pilot that never gets tired,
실수도 없고 지치지도 않는
조종사가 모는
제트 여객기를 상상해봐
never makes mistakes.
never shows up with a hangover.
술이 덜 깬 채
출근하는 일도 없는
Meet the pilot.
그런 조종사를 말야
Why did we get married?
Have children? You don't need us.
우린 왜 결혼했어?
애들은 뭐하러 낳고
우린 안중에도 없잖아
당신 정신은 온통
여기에만 쏠려있어
Your heart and your mind
are in here.
하지만 이게 우리만큼
당신을 사랑해주진 않아
But it doesn't love you like we do.
미안해, 진심이야
I'm sorry. Really.
당분간 다른 애들과
보내는 건 어때?
How about spending some time
with your other babies?
야, 이게 누구야?
Raging Waters?
- Yeah!
차 안에 있어요
Wait in the car.
엔리케, 여기 있는 거야?
Enrique?
You here?
여전히 빈틈없군
Pretty jumpy, Connor.
당신도 여전해
What about you?
능청도 여전하고
Always on the lurk.
만나서 반가워
Good to see you, Connor.
- I promised to make it back.
- 잘 있었어?
- 물론, 난 걱정 없지
Man, I knew it.
Good to see you.
욜란다, 반가운 손님이 왔으니까
술상 차려, 데낄라로...
Yolanda. Get out here, we got
company. And bring some tequila!
존도 잘 있었니?
Oye. Big John?
Que pasa?
- What's up?
별일 없으시죠?
Who's your friend?
- He's cool.
저 친구는 누구야?
대단한 분이죠
우리편이에요
He's with me. He is Uncle Bob.
이분은 밥 삼촌이에요
삼촌, 이쪽은 엔리케예요
Uncle Bob, this is Enrique.
삼촌이라고?
Uncle Bob, huh?
알았다
Okay.
How are you?
- 안녕하세요?
- 정말 많이 컸구나
How are you? You've gotten big.
정말 많이 컸어
마시겠소?
Drink?
밥 삼촌이라고?
Uncle Bob?
Sarahlita, you pretty famous.
꽤 유명하더군
TV에 당신들 세 명이 나왔어
All over the TV. Pictures of
you, John, your big friend here.
사진도 나오고 대단해
Cops are going nuts looking for you.
경찰도 찾느라 아주 난리야
그런데 무슨 일이야?
Take the kid, honey, will you?
I just came for my stuff.
내 물건 때문에 온 거야
옷과 음식, 트럭이 필요해
I need clothes, food.
and one of your trucks.
그럼 난 어떻게 하라고 그래?
How about the fillings out of
my fucking teeth? - Now.
당장 필요해
둘은 무기 점검을 하도록 해
You two, you're on weapons detail.
- Come on, let's go.
이쪽으로 가요
우리 엄만 다른 건 몰라도...
One thing about my mom.
준비 하나는 철저하죠
she always plans ahead.
Excellent.
훌륭하군
Nothing down here.
여기선 제일 좋은 트럭인데
모터가 고장났어
This is the best truck I got.
but the starter is gone.
고칠 시간은 좀 있나?
You got the time to change it out?
- Yeah.
조금, 어두워야 국경을
넘을 거니까
I'm gonna wait till dark
to cross the border.
엔리께!
Enrique, it's dangerous for you here.
여기 있으면 위험해
당신도 오늘밤에 떠나!
You get out tonight too, okay?
- Sure.
알았어
생각나면 언제든지
들르라고, 알았지?
Just drop by any time
and totally fuck up my life.
전 이런 곳에서 자랐어요
See. I grew up in places like this,
그래서 모든 사람들이
이렇게 사는 줄 알았어요
so I thought
that's how people lived:
헬기를 타고
riding around in helicopters,
총 쏘는 걸 배우면서요
Iearning how to blow shit up.
하지만 엄마가 체포되고
But then, when my mom got busted,
I got put in a regular school.
나도 학교로 보내졌어요
The other kids were into Nintendo.
다른 애들은 전자게임에
빠져있을 때죠
두려워해 본 적 있어요?
Are you ever afraid?
No.
아니
죽는 것도?
Not even of dying?
없어
No.
죽음에 대해
아무 느낌도 없는 거예요?
You don't feel any emotion about it
one way or another?
No.
I have to stay functional
없어, 단지 임무를 수행할 때까지
살아남는 거야
until the mission is complete.
죽는 건 상관 안 해
Then it doesn't matter.
Yeah. I have to stay functional too.
I'm "too important".
나도 살아남아야 해요
중요한 인물이니까
정말 잘 어울려요
That's definitely you.
Most of the guys my mom
hung round with were geeks.
이 아저씨 빼고는 엄마 친구들은
다 별 볼 일 없는 사람들이었어요
But there was this one guy.
He was kinda cool.
He taught me engines.
엔진 기술도 가르쳐줬어요
여기를 잡아
Hold here.
Mom screwed it up, of course.
결국 엄마가 망쳐버렸죠
언제나 심판의 날이니
She'd always tell
them about Judgment Day
민중의 지도자니 하는
and me being this world leader.
얘기만 떠들어댔거든요
And that'll be all she wrote.
Torque wrench, please.
- Here.
토크랜치!
여기요!
아빠를 만나고 싶어요
I wish I could've met my real dad.
만날 거야
You will.
그러겠죠
Yeah. I guess.
When I'm, like, 45, I think.
제가 45살 때쯤이나...
제가 1984년으로
아버지를 보냈대요
I'll send him back
through time to 1984.
세상에...
아직 태어나지도 않으신 분이죠
He hasn't even been born yet.
생각하면 복잡해져요
It messes with your head.
- 볼트!
- 여기요
The other bolt.
Here.
엄마 아빠는 하루밖에
같이 못 보냈지만
Mom and him
were only together one night.
아직도 사랑하시나봐요
She still loves him, I guess.
가끔 우시는 걸 봤거든요
I see her crying sometimes.
눈에 뭐가 들어갔다면서
절대로 아닌 척 했지만요
She denies it totally, of course.
Like she got something
stuck in her eye.
왜 우는 거지?
Why do you cry?
- 사람들 말인가요?
- 그래
You mean people?
- Yeah.
모르겠어요
I don't know.
그냥 우는 거예요
We just cry, you know.
아플 때도 울구요
When it hurts.
꼭 아프면 우는 건가?
Pain causes it?
No, it's different.
아뇨, 뭐 꼭 그런 건 아녜요
별일도 아닌데
눈물이 날 때도 있죠
It's when there's nothing wrong
but you hurt anyway.
- 이해 돼요?
- 아니
You get it?
- No.
오, 멋진데요
Alright! My man!
문제없지
No problemo.
우리 파이팅해요
Gimme five.
손을 이렇게 내밀어 봐요
Put out your hand like this.
Come on.
좋아요! 다시 한번 해요
내 손을 쳐요! 쳐보라니까요!
Alright. Now hit me.
Gimme five. Do the same thing.
- Alright!
아주 좋았어요
한번 더!
Okay, that's good.
Up high, up high.
자, 여기...
Five low.
Too slow.
왜 이렇게 느려요?
농담이에요
한번 더 해봐요
Just kidding.
One more time.
한번 더 해보자니까요!
좋아요! 자...
기계인간과 같이 있는 존을
보면서 모든 걸 확실히 느꼈다
Watching John with the machine,
it was suddenly so clear.
터미네이터는 절대 멈추지도 않고
The Terminator would never stop.
it would never leave him.
존을 떠나지도 않을 것이다
never hurt him,
술에 취해 고함을 지르고
때리지도 않을 것이고
never shout at him
or get drunk and hit him.
바쁘다고 외면하지도
않을 것이다
or say it was too busy
to spend time with him.
It would always be there.
항상 존 옆에 머물면서
목숨을 걸고 존을 보호할 것이다
And it would die to protect him.
이 기계만이 지금은
존의 아버지를 대신할
Of all the would-be fathers
who came and went.
자격을 갖추고 있으며
this thing, this machine.
was the only one who measured up.
유일한 우리의 희망이다
지금의 현실로는
In an insane world.
it was the sanest choice.
가장 현명한 방법 같다
자, 이거 타볼까?
자, 여기!
'운명이란 없다'
애를 데리고 남쪽으로 가래요
She said you go south with him.
- 내일 만나자고 하던데요
- 엄마!
She'll meet you tomorrow.
- Mom !
Mom! Wait!
엄마, 기다려요!
운명이란 없다
"No fate."
우리가 만든 것 밖에는...
No fate but what we make.
아빠의 말씀이에요
My father told her this.
미래의 제가 아버지를 통해
엄마에게 보낸 메시지예요
I mean, I made him memorize it, up
in the future, as a message to her.
신경 쓰지 마세요
Never mind.
Now okay,
현재는 진행되고 있어요
the whole thing goes:
"The future is not set.
미래는 정해진 것도 아니고
그러니 운명이란 건 없다구요
우리가 만드는 거라구요
There is no fate
but what we make for ourselves."
네 엄마는 미래를 바꾸러 간 거야
She intends to change the future.
그런 것 같아요
Yeah, I guess.
나, 참!
Oh shit!
- 다이슨이군
- 맞아요
Dyson.
Yeah, gotta be!
바로 그 자예요
마일스 다이슨!
Miles Dyson!
그 자를 죽이러 간 거라구요
She's gonna blow him away!
빨리 가요, 빨리요!
Come on! Let's go!
이건 위험한 짓이야
This is tactically dangerous.
- Drive faster.
더 빨리 몰아요!
T-1000은 나와 같은
구조 파일로 돼 있어
The T-1000 has
the same files that I do.
내가 아는 건 녀석도 알아
우리가 뭘 할지 알고 있을 거야
It knows what I know.
It might anticipate this move.
상관없어요
엄마를 막아야 해요
I don't care. We've gotta stop her.
다이슨만 죽인다면
전쟁도 막을 수 있어
Killing Dyson might actually
prevent the war. - I don't care!
그게 문제가 아니라
아직도 모르겠어요?
Haven't you learnt anything yet?
Why you can't kill people?
사람을 함부로 죽이면
안 되는 거예요
아저씨가 살든 죽든
상관 안 한다고
Look, maybe you don't care
if you live or die.
다른 사람들까지 그런 건 아녜요
But everybody's not like that!
We have feelings.
우린 감정도 있고, 고통도 알고
두려워도 한다구요
We hurt. We're afraid.
You gotta learn this stuff.
I'm not kidding. It's important.
이점만은 꼭 알아둬요
정말 중요한 문제예요
Danny, I told you
to go to bed like your sister.
대니, 침실로 가라고 했잖아
엄마 화낸다!
조금만 더 놀게요, 엄마
Just a couple of minutes, Mom.
대니, 시간 됐어
Danny, your time is up.
양치질하고 가서 자
Come brush your teeth
and get to bed.
대니!
아빠!
Danny just go!
대니, 어서 나가라! 어서!
여보!
- 애들 데리고 가
- 하느님 맙소사!
Oh my God !
대니 데리고 빨리 도망쳐
Just take Danny and go. Run!
빨리!
오, 이런... 여보!
Oh Jesus. Miles.
아빠!
- 대니! 대니, 안 돼!
- 모두 꼼짝 마!
Nobody fucking move!
아빠 쏘지 말아요
Don't hurt my daddy!
Get on the floor!
바닥에 엎드려!
엎드려!
Fucking down! Now!
Get out of the way!
어서 비켜!
아빠 해치지 말아요
Don't hurt him!
Get on the floor! Fast!
바닥에 엎드려!
Just let the boy go.
애는 보내 줘요
닥쳐, 닥쳐!
Shut up! Shut up!
닥쳐! 입 닥치라구!
모두 당신 잘못이야
It's all your fault!
- 다 당신 때문이라구
- 뭐가요?
It's all your fault!
- What?
절대 그냥 두지 않겠어
I'm not gonna let you do it.
너무 늦었나 봐요
Shit, we're too late.
저들을 봐줘요
Check them.
엄마, 날 봐요!
Look at me, Mom.
Are you hurt?
괜찮아요?
Look at me.
하마터면...
I almost...
이제 괜찮아요
It'll by okay.
We'll figure something out, okay?
다 잘 될 거예요
약속할게요
Promise.
그래, 날 막으러 왔구나
You came here to stop me?
그래요
Yes, I did.
널 사랑한다, 존
I love you, John.
항상 사랑했다
I always have.
알아요
I know.
총알이 뚫고 갔소
Clean penetration.
뼈는 괜찮군
No shattered bone.
여길 꽉 잡으시오
피를 멈추게 해야 하니까
Hold here. Compression
should stop the bleeding.
당신들은 누구요?
Who are you?
보여줘요
Show him.
대니, 날 따라와
네 방 구경 좀 시켜줄래?
Danny, I want you to come with me.
Show me your room.
Oh, my God !
이럴 수가
내 말을 잘 들으시오
Now listen to me very carefully.
Dyson listened while
the Terminator laid it all down.
터미네이터가 모든 걸 알려줬고
다이슨은 조용히 듣고 있었다
스카이넷과 심판의 날
Skynet, Judgment Day,
the history of things to come.
앞으로 벌어질 역사
It's not every day that you find out
다이슨은 자신이 미래에
30억 인구를
you're responsible
for 3 billion deaths.
죽인다는 사실을
잘 받아들였다
He took it pretty well.
토할 것 같소
I feel like I'm gonna throw up.
아직 하지도 않은 일을
You're judging me
심판하러 왔군요
on things I haven't even done yet.
How were we
supposed to know?
우리가 어떻게 그걸 알았겠소?
그래
Yeah. Right.
맞아
How were you supposed to know?
당신은 그걸 알 길이 없었겠지
Fucking men like you
built the hydrogen bomb.
당신 같은 사람이
수소폭탄을 만들고
Men like you thought it up.
이 모든 비극을 생각해낸 거야
창조적이라고 떠들어대면서
You think you're so creative.
You don't know what it's like
to create something.
진짜 창조가 뭔지도 모르지
To create a life.
생명의 의미가 뭔지...
To feel it growing inside you.
생명이 어떻게 자라는 지도 몰라
죽음밖에 창조할 줄 모르지
죽음밖에
All you know how to create
is death and destruction. - Mom!
엄마!
We need to be a little more
constructive here, okay?
지금은 누굴 비방할 때가 아니라
앞으로의 사태를
수습할 방법을 생각해야 되잖아요
We still have to
stop this from happening.
그렇다면...
But I thought...
지금 이 순간 우리가
역사를 바꾸려하는 거군요
Aren't we changing things?
Changing the way it goes?
지금 당장
마이크로 연구를 포기하고
That's right!
There's no way I'm gonna
finish the processor. Not now.
내일 사이버다인에 사표를 내겠소
Forget it. I'm out of it.
I quit Cyberdyne tomorrow.
- Not good enough.
그 정도론 부족해요
No one must follow your work.
- Right, then...
누구도 그 연구를
계속하면 안 돼요
그래요
연구실에 있는 파일, 디스크 등
We have to destroy the stuff
at the lab. The files, drives...
모든 자료를 없애겠소
Everything. Everything here.
정말이오
모두 말이오
Everything! I don't care.
전 괜찮아요
칩...
Do you know about the chip?
- What chip?
- 칩에 대해서도 압니까?
- 칩이라니?
In a vault at Cyberdyne.
From the other one like you.
연구실에 있는데 당신 같은
인조인간으로부터 구했대요
첫 번째 터미네이터의 것이군
The CPU from the first terminator.
Son of a bitch. I knew it!
나쁜 놈들
내가 그럴 줄 알았어
They told us
not to ask where they got it.
어디서 구했는지
묻지 말라고 하더군요
Those lying motherfuckers!
나쁜 자식들
It was radically advanced.
놀라운 물건이오
급진적인 발전이었죠
It was smashed, it didn't work.
But it gave us ideas.
완전히 부서져서
작동도 안 되는 기계였지만
새로운 연구의 계기가 됐어요
took us in new directions.
Things we'd never...
전혀 새로운 것들이죠
내 연구도 거기서 시작된 거요
All my work is based on it.
- It must be destroyed.
그것을 없애야 하오
우리가 그 안에 들어갈 수 있을까요?
Can you get us in, past security?
I think so, yeah.
그럼요, 그럼 언제?
When?
Now?
지금?
언제나 선명했던 미래는
The future, always so clear to me.
지금 한밤의 고속도로 같았다
had become like
a black highway at night.
We were
in uncharted territory now,
우린 역사에 기억되지 않을
새로운 역사를 만들 것이다
making up history as we went along.
사이버다인 시스템
안녕하시오?
당신, 칼 맞죠?
Hi.
Carl, right?
날 찾아온 친구들인데
Friends from outta town,
Thought I'd...
연구소를 구경시켜 주려고 왔소
...show them around.
다이슨 씨, 방문객 규칙을
잘 알잖아요
You know
the rules concerning visitors.
I need authorization...
허가가 나와야...
난 들어가겠소
I insist.
꺼낼 생각도 하지 마
Don't even think about it.
됐소
두 개의 열쇠를 동시에 돌려야
열려요, 아시겠어요?
Takes 2 keys to open the vault.
turned simultaneously.
나머지 한 개는 경비실에 있어요
The other one is
at the security station.
기빈스!
Gibbons.
기빈스, 어딨어?
Come on, man.
you can't leave the desk like that.
이렇게 비워두면 어떡해?
이런 젠장!
Oh, shit.
카드가 접속이 안 되고 있어요
My card should access this.
What is it?
- Dammit.
- 왜 그래요?
- 제기랄!
The silent alarm's been tripped.
경보가 울리고 있소
모든 암호를 정지시켜 건물 안의
It's neutralized
all the codes in the building.
어떤 문도 열리지 않을 거요
Nothing'll open anywhere now.
We have to abort.
포기를 해야 합니다
No.
We do it all the way! Okay?
끝까지 할 거예요, 알았어요?
연구실이나 처리해요
제가 이걸 열 테니까요
You guys get started on the lab.
I can open this.
I think it's that guy
from the mall. - It is the guy!
- 신문에 난 남자 같아요
- 맞아요
그 사람들이에요
Him and the woman.
지금 당장 모든 병력을
보내 주세요
Just send everything
you've got in the area.
I have a personal entry code
for the lab that may still work.
연구실의 개인 암호는 될 거요
소용이 없군요
It's no good.
- Let me try mine.
내 식대로 하겠소
존, 문을 폭파시킬 거야
John! Fire-in-the-hole!
기다려요! 지금 들어가면 안 돼요
화재 경보장치가 가동됐어요
Wait! You can't go in there!
The fire's set off the halo system !
You have to wait a few minutes,
until the gas clears.
가스가 없어질 때까지 기다려요
이걸 써요
Put this on.
좋아요, 일을 시작해요
Alright, let's get to work.
모든 경찰에게 알린다
출동 가능 지역 경찰들은
All units in the vicinity.
all units able to respond:
지금 모두 사이버다인 건물로
집결하기 바란다
A 211 in progress at 2144 Kramer
Street, the Cyberdyne building.
건물로 침입한 범인은
Suspect 1 is white, female.
사라 코너라는 백인 여자로
identified as: last name Connor.
first name Sarah,
어제 정신병원에서 탈출했다
escaped from
Pescadero State Hospital.
또 한 명은 백인 남자로...
Suspect 2: white, male...
내가 쓰는 디스크 전부예요
All the disks in my office. All the
disks in that office over there.
저쪽에도 있어요
내 책상 뒤에...
Everything behind my desk.
칩들은 전부 왼쪽에
All the processors on my left.
폭탄으로 날려버릴 거예요
We'll blow it up with the CP4.
저기...
Could I ...
Excuse me...
실례합니다
그것 좀 빌려줄래요?
Could I borrow that thing?
지난 수년간 이 문제를 연구했어요
I worked a lot
of years on this thing.
1-메리-23
위치 다시 알려주기 바란다!
Give me that location again.
- 2111 , Kramer.
크레이머가 2111번지
둘은 모두 중무장한
위험인물들이다
The suspects are armed and
considered extremely dangerous.
좋아
Alright,
7-2-5-6
"7-2-5-6.
Yes!
쉬운데!
Easy money.
젠장! 이럴 수가!
Oh, shit.
Not good. Not good.
다 됐나요?
How we doing?
- Primal cord is set.
뇌관은 됐어요
하나만 더 설치하면 돼요
2분 정도 걸릴 거요
One more barrel.
two more minutes.
- 어떻게 폭파시킬 거죠?
- 원격조종장치로...
How do we set them off?
- Remote control.
쉽군
Piece of cake.
We got company.
- Police?
- 문제가 생겼어요
- 경찰?
- 몇 명이나?
- 사방에 깔렸어요
How many?
- All of them, I think.
여긴 내가 책임질 테니까
모두 가요
Go! I'll finish here.
가죠
경찰은 내가 처리하겠어
I'll take care of the police.
- Wait, you swore...
또 약속 잊었군요
날 믿어
Trust me.
창가에 있는 자!
Hey you at the window,
지금 당장 총을 버리고
항복하라, 항복하라
drop your weapon and place
your hands on top of your head.
제길
발칸포를 갖고 있다
That's a damn mini-gun!
- 피해!
- 젠장!
Come on! Go!
빨리 뛰어! 어서!
Go! Go!
인명피해 : 0
Fire!
발사!
동시에 왼쪽으로 돌려
We go the same time to the left.
One, two, three, go!
하나, 둘, 셋, 돌려!
됐어, 이제 그걸 꺼내려면...
Alright.
In order to get that out, you...
이제 스카이넷은 잡은 거예요
We got Skynet by the balls now.
don't we? Come on, let's book!
가요, 서둘러요
사격 중지!
Hold your fire!
- 폭발 준비 됐나요?
- 그래
Ready to rock?
- Ready.
갈 시간이오
Time to go. Now.
당장!
- 이걸 써! 가스를 사용할 거야
- 가요!
Take this. They'll use gas.
문 쪽부터 폭파해요
마일스, 뇌관을 갖다줘요
Get started on the door.
Miles, hand me the detonator.
엄마! 엄마!
Mom! Mom !
젠장!
엄마가 갇혔어
빠져나올 길이 없어요
Shit! She's in the clean room.
There's no way out of there.
엎드려!
Get down!
이리 줘
Here.
더 이상 못 들고 있겠어요
I don't know how much longer
I can hold this.
후퇴하라!
Fall back!
모두 빨리 나가!
Everybody out!
빨리 움직여! 빨리!
Move it! Now! Go!
전쟁이 따로 없군
We have a war zone here.
위험대상
눈을 감아
Shut your eyes.
여기 있어요
곧 돌아올게요
Stay here. I'll be back.
바닥에 엎드려!
Down on the floor, face down!
어서 엎드려!
On the floor, now!
좋다, 발사!
Okay, drop him !
이걸 좀 들고 있어
Here, hold this.
젠장!
가!
Go!
맙소사!
꺼져!
Get out!
잘 들어!
Listen, no matter what happens,
you stay under these vests.
무슨 일이 있어도 이 방탄복
뒤에 숨어 있거라
- 알았지?
- 네
You got it?
- Yeah.
됐다
헬기가 따라 와요
Chopper is coming in!
- It's him.
바로 그 놈이요
이런!
존, 몸을 숙여!
Stay down!
Hello?
이럴 수가!
Goddamn,
당신 괜찮소?
you alright?
어서요, 엄마!
나가야 돼요
Come on, Mom.
we gotta get out.
총도 들어라
Take the shotgun.
- Okay.
많이 다쳤소?
Are you hurt?
이런!
Holy shit. Come on!
엄마, 가요!
빨리 서둘러요
당신 트럭 좀 씁시다
We need your truck.
- Hurry!
어서 가요!
- 어서요
- 타!
Hurry!
- Get in.
어서요!
이게 뭐야!
What the hell...
- 출혈이 심해!
- 계속 지압해요
I'm bleeding bad !
- Keep pressure on it.
Here, this'll work.
이걸로 묶어요
따라오고 있어요
He's gaining !
더 밟아요
Step on it!
- This is the vehicle's top speed.
- 이게 최고 속도야
- 더 빨리 달릴 수 있어요
I can get out
and run faster than this!
오른쪽으로 오고 있어요
He's coming up, to the right.
조심해요!
- 대신 운전 해
- 어쩌려구요?
Drive a minute.
- Where the hell are you going?
오른쪽 길로 빠져!
Take the off ramp.
이런!
꽉 잡아요
Hold on!
멈추면 안 돼
Don't stop!
직진해
Go straight!
피해!
모두 피해!
빨리 피해!
Get the hell out of here!
여기서 모두 나가요!
빨리!
Get out of here. Let's go!
다음에 또 보자, 친구
Hasta la vista, baby.
시간이 얼마 없어
We don't have much time.
가자!
Let's go!
빨리요, 엄마!
어서 나가야 돼요
Come on, we gotta get out of here!
일어나요
Get up!
총 이리 주세요
Hand me the shotgun.
움직여 봐요
Put your weight on me, Mom.
어서요!
Hurry!
힘내요, 엄마!
Come on, Mom !
어서 일어나요
Come on, Mom, get up!
이쪽으로 갑시다! 빨리!
This way. Come on!
Wait.
잠깐, 여긴 너무 뜨거워요
Wait, no, it's too hot.
뒤로 돌아가요
Go back!
- 뒤로 먼저 가
- 같이 가야 해요
Run!
- No, we stick together.
존, 빨리 도망가!
John, you gotta go now.
- 존!
- 가! 빨리!
Go now!
- No!
추적
계단을 올라가!
Take these steps. Go.
빨리!
올라가!
Help me.
- I got you. Come on.
엄마, 빨리 가요
자, 체인을 잡아!
Grab the chain. Grab it!
잡고 내려가! 어서!
Grab it! Go!
엄마, 내려와요! 어서요!
Mom! Come on!
존을 부르시지
Call to John.
No.
몹시 아플 텐데
I know this hurts.
존을 불러라
Call John.
당장 존을 불러
Call to John now.
헛소리 마
Fuck you.
대체 에너지
John! Help!
도와다오
John!
엄마!
Help me.
도와줘
비켜라, 존!
Out of the way, John!
쏴요!
Shoot!
엎드려!
Down!
일어나요, 어서!
Get up.
Come on.
이런!
Holy shit!
나도 휴가가 필요해
I need a vacation.
죽었을까요?
Is it dead?
제거됐어
Terminated.
이것도 없애야겠죠?
Will this melt in there?
그래, 던져 버려
Yes. Throw it in.
Adios.
잘 가라
칩도 버려
And the chip.
It's over.
이제 다 끝났어
No.
아직 칩이 하나 더 있소
There is one more chip.
이것도 제거돼야 하오
And it must be
destroyed also.
자!
Here.
내가 직접 할 수 없으니
당신이 날 용광로에 넣어 주시오
I can't self-terminate.
You must lower me into the steel.
No!
- 미안하다, 존... 미안해
- 안 돼
I'm sorry, John.
가면 안 돼요
우린 같은 편이잖아요
It'll be okay. Stay with us!
- 가지 마요
- 나도 가야 한다
I have to go away.
- No don't do it, please don't go.
안 돼요
제발 가지 말아요
가야 한다, 존
I must go away, John.
- No.
안 돼요, 기다려요
No, wait.
이럴 필요까진 없어요
You don't have to.
미안하다, 존
Sorry.
이러지 말아요, 거기 서요
No, don't do it, don't go!
여기서 끝내야 돼
It has to end here.
가지 마!
가지 말라고 내가 명령하잖아!
I order you not to go.
네가 왜 우는지 알고 있다
I know now why you cry.
인간만이 흘릴 수 있지
But it's something I can never do.
잘 있거라
Goodbye.
미지의 미래는
우리를 향해 오고 있다
The unknown future
rolls toward us.
내 인생 처음으로 희망을
알게 되었다
I face it for the first time
with a sense of hope.
터미네이터라는 기계조차
Because if a machine, a terminator.
깨달은 생명의 가치를
can learn the value of human life.
우리 역시 배울 수 있을 것이다.
maybe we can too.
Subtitles : ?2002 soul^keeper